[{"id": "5a9e92c77ccba3ffe45786bc", "question": "In which book does Flora refers to Mr. Meyerburg as Mr. Mybug?", "answer": "Cold Comfort Farm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc8606de0eb824d4052fb", "question": "Where is the world's largest Roman aqueduct that is still in use?", "answer": "Spain -- The Segovia aqueduct, built in the first century A.D., carries water from the Fuente Fr\u00eda River to the city of Segovia.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af2a", "question": "The Bren light machine gun originated in which then country?", "answer": "Czechoslovakia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a05720565ad31a57c794", "question": "What historical ruler instituted one of the first international postal services?", "answer": "Genghis Khan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909d246bb53d1af65886507", "question": "Which star is represented by placing a star on top of a Christmas tree?", "answer": "Star of Bethlehem", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86a", "question": "What is the more common name for benzoic sulfinide?", "answer": "Saccharin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cdc83e347d002c297e4e8", "question": "In 1973 Roland Ohisson was buried in a coffin made of what?", "answer": "Chocolate", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c40a", "question": "Which tree is the only nut-bearer native to North America?", "answer": "Pecan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ca3d3544f0f6af5b066638", "question": "What is the color of the Italian liqeuer Galliano?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7cb41877e98cb97778a17", "question": "The ancient Phoenician city of Constantine is located in what modern-day Arab country?", "answer": "Algeria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e7a", "question": "Which TV show used the song \"A Little Less Conversation\" by Elvis Presley as its theme song?", "answer": "Las Vegas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb1", "question": "What are the seven deadly sins?", "answer": "Greed, Envy, Gluttony, Sloth, Lust, Pride And Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f3", "question": "What fruit was once called a Persian apple?", "answer": "Peach", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba9e", "question": "What food company produces the cereals Count Chocula, Franken Berry, and Boo Berry?", "answer": "General Mills", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c413", "question": "What name is given to an elephant's second incisors?", "answer": "Tusks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f6", "question": "What sport do Fuzzy Zoeller and Kermit Zarley play?", "answer": "Golf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa55a6ce05a3942286ebf", "question": "What was Arnold Schwarzenegger's character's name in the film \"Total Recall\"?", "answer": "Dennis Quaid", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8b0", "question": "Which company manufactured the B-29 Superfortress aircraft?", "answer": "Boeing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c489", "question": "What is the term for the visible surface of the Sun?", "answer": "Photosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a433", "question": "What is the capital of Spain?", "answer": "Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071f1e3745b36be73039e8", "question": "What is the full name of Em Cypress, Dana's sister and reviver, in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Martha Ann Cypress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c0b", "question": "Who won a Pulitzer Prize for his novel \"The Old Man and the Sea\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e8e", "question": "In Botticelli's \"The Birth of Venus\", what is Venus standing on as she rides to shore?", "answer": "A seashell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b333", "question": "What was founded in the UK in 1694 because of war with France?", "answer": "Bank of England", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a553a03e1c6f9840ba31a6", "question": "In which popular 1950s film is a character played by Audrey Hepburn given 24 hours to do as she pleases in the eternal city?", "answer": "Roman Holiday", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c89a", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the inventor of dynamite?", "answer": "Nobelium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff214fe31a458464a93c45b", "question": "Who came up with \"The Allegory of the Cave\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6017381644491cbd7c5a1794", "question": "During World War II, prisoners wearing an inverted pink triangle in a concentration camp signified the prisoners were what?", "answer": "Primarily homosexual men, bisexual\u00a0men,\u00a0transgender women and sexual offenders, as well as,\u00a0pedophiles\u00a0and\u00a0zoophiles.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5aab2f0058d116dab4aecb45", "question": "What is the scientific method of dating tree rings called?", "answer": "Dendrochronology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a079", "question": "What record company did Berry Gordy Jr. start in 1959?", "answer": "Motown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab2b", "question": "What is the capital of Fiji?", "answer": "Suva", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a552683e1c6f9840ba3195", "question": "Where was the Armistice of 11 November 1918 signed?", "answer": "Compiegne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c5680775fa611bce67c6", "question": "Mustard seeds aren't actually spicy until what happens?", "answer": "They're crushed - A compound called sinigrin is released, and when mixed with cold water, creates a paste that can burn your skin.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb47", "question": "Within 3 years, either way, in what year did Lou Gehrig deliver his famous farewell speech at Yankee Stadium?", "answer": "1939", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b48a", "question": "Which country were the 1992 Summer Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beb2", "question": "What item would a tailor measure in lignes?", "answer": "A button", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ca", "question": "Which great battle took place from July 1 to November 18, 1916?", "answer": "The Battle of the Somme", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f164e96f9b80650dbe7f935", "question": "What color is the \"Space stone\" in the 2017 Marvel Legacy relaunch?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c021", "question": "Which fashion designer was shot dead in the summer of 1997?", "answer": "Gianni Versace", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b37701dd7bf43be5e7b0", "question": "A kindle is a group of what animals?", "answer": "Kittens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f5", "question": "What actor played the role of Jean-Baptiste Emanuel Zorg in the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Gary Oldman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc8816de0eb824d4052fc", "question": "What is Camp David's official name?", "answer": "Naval Support Facility Thurmont -- President Eisenhower named it Camp David after his grandson, David.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600781fabd51d85e222ab651", "question": "What is the title of Henri Matisse's famous portrait of his wife?", "answer": "In 1905, just prior to such works being derisively labeled as the creations of Les Fauves, he painted\u00a0\"The Green Stripe\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b149", "question": "What Egyptian pharaoh was known as \"The Boy King\"?", "answer": "Tutankhamen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a0", "question": "What Sioux tribe did Sitting Bull belong to?", "answer": "The Lakota", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c6", "question": "What vitamin is sometimes referred to as the \"sunshine vitamin\"?", "answer": "Vitamin D", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b61d", "question": "What type of salad was invented by the owner of the Hollywood eatery the Brown Derby?", "answer": "The Cobb Salad", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6a47b6c0f9723ab15cb54", "question": "Who was USA' first female governor?", "answer": "Nellie Tayloe Ross", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f45", "question": "What sheriff's alter ego was the masked \"El Kabong\"?", "answer": "Quick Draw McGraw's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f3c", "question": "According to Erma Bombeck's best seller, where is the grass always greener?", "answer": "Over the septic tank", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133943d", "question": "What 2000 movie depicts the war on drugs in Ohio, California and Mexico?", "answer": "Traffic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b7e", "question": "Who played Lex Luthor in the 2006 film \"Superman Returns\"?", "answer": "Kevin Spacey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd536e347d002c297e4b6", "question": "Which book did James Fenimore Cooper publish in 1826 that was later made into a movie, starring Daniel Day-Lewis?", "answer": "The Last of the Mohicans", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338952", "question": "What kind of creatures are Nag and Nagaina who plan to kill Rikki-Tikki-Tavi in \"The Jungle Book\"?", "answer": "Cobras", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e2", "question": "Who is the director of the movie \"Jurassic Park\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cc98877e98cb97778a27", "question": "What is the biggest island in Canada?", "answer": "Baffin Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac7", "question": "What sport is the subject of the book \"Sands of Time\"?", "answer": "Beach volleyball", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c10", "question": "What is comedian Stephen Colbert's full birth name?", "answer": "Stephen Tyrone Colbert", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b62a", "question": "What are known as \"buddy stores\"?", "answer": "Aircraft fuel tanks", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba48", "question": "What US city hosts the world's largest hot air balloon festival?", "answer": "Albuquerque", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae4d", "question": "In 1819, the US purchased Florida from what country?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "history"}, {"id": "592eb148f83302ff91e464a6", "question": "Who played the role of Joanna in the film \"Office Space\"?", "answer": "Jennifer Aniston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc3536ce05a3942286f22", "question": "What is the name of Jack Nicholson's character in the film, \"Chinatown\"?", "answer": "J.J \"Jake\" Gittes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ccff877e98cb97778a30", "question": "What shape is in the center of Switzerland's flag?", "answer": "Cross", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60062c0dc9d816e292245c28", "question": "What art movement was Yoko Ono associated with during the 1960s?", "answer": "Yoko Ono helped to define the\u00a0Fluxus\u00a0movement in 1960s  New York, which was part Dada, part Bauhaus and part Zen.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600243bf4be4723ccac2219b", "question": "What is the name of Emily Bronte\u2019s only completed novel?", "answer": "Wuthering Heights", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a241", "question": "Who played Inspector Morse in the TV series by the same name?", "answer": "John Thaw", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf1", "question": "What is the world\u2019s largest diamond company?", "answer": "De Beers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e91070ad7247dfc0fa00317", "question": "Which actor plays the DC hero Wild Dog on the TV show \"Arrow\"?", "answer": "Rick Gonzalez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d1f", "question": "What sport is the focus of the movie \"The Color of Money\"?", "answer": "Pool", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aec4", "question": "Who was burnt at the stake by the English at Rouen on May 30th 1431?", "answer": "Joan of Arc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0fe", "question": "The flowers of the curry tree are what color?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b852", "question": "What two baseball players make up the battery?", "answer": "The pitcher and the catcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a48e", "question": "What is the largest city of Madeira?", "answer": "Funchal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bfdffbdb668d7dfe168b5bb", "question": "This ancient attempt to transmute base metals into noble metals was called what?", "answer": "Alchemy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf10", "question": "Which type of restaurant popularized the use of conveyor belts?", "answer": "Sushi Restaurants\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f6eb9a9e54d890926f6c9", "question": "From what did the Caribbean derive its name?", "answer": "Indigenous people - The word \"Carib\" refers to one of the Amerindian groups on the islands when they were discovered by Europeans.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339139", "question": "In pulp magazines, who was referred to as \"The Man of Bronze\"?", "answer": "Doc Savage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c39e", "question": "What bird bone is known as the \"wishbone\"?", "answer": "Collarbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b5", "question": "Death Valley is located in which US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba7d", "question": "What Italian chicken dish\u2019s name means \u201chunter\u2019s chicken\u201d?", "answer": "Chicken cacciatore", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133947a", "question": "In the movie \"Lilo and Stitch\", what city does Stitch build and then destroy in the bedroom?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b527", "question": "What are you supposed to do when presented with the wine cork from a freshly opened wine bottle?", "answer": "Look at it", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9ea", "question": "What is it that turns red litmus paper blue?", "answer": "Basic solution", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338957", "question": "What is by far the most famous painting in the Louvre?", "answer": "The Mona Lisa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a683", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Treasure State\"?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff51402ff04d658268c92e0", "question": "What Chinese princess commanded the \"Army of the Lady\"?", "answer": "Princess Pingyang,\u00a0the daughter of Emperor Gaozu of Tang", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c0", "question": "In pool, what color is the 6-ball?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133939b", "question": "What is the name of Dr. Evil's cat in the movie \"Austin Powers: International Man of Mystery\"?", "answer": "Mr. Bigglesworth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be2e", "question": "What dish, named for a famous general, is coated in foie gras, mushrooms, and puff pastry?", "answer": "Beef Wellington", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e07afe83fe1f2a824b8d", "question": "Which Old West figure became sports editor for the \"New York Morning Telegraph?\"", "answer": "William Barclay \"Bat\" Masterson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c77cf2f24f0f7a362efd54c", "question": "How many claws in total does the average adult cat have?", "answer": "18", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f63", "question": "What actor blogs at \"Schrute-Space\" at NBC.com?", "answer": "Rainn Wilson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c81", "question": "What famous American author published Ulysses S. Grant's \"Personal Memoirs\"?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff665d952a821ff76ae8af4", "question": "What was the first Times Square New Year Eve\u2019s ball made of?", "answer": "The first Times Square New Year Eve's ball was made of iron and wood.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b470", "question": "Which politician was given the nickname Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefa5fb6ce05a3942286ec8", "question": "Who directed the film \"Home Alone?\"", "answer": "Chris Columbus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e74", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"City Lights\"?", "answer": "Virginia Cherrill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a372", "question": "What is the capital of Iraq?", "answer": "Baghdad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffaf31cf6db9ac4808cf2", "question": "Which was the last contiguous U.S. territory to obtain statehood?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fb1beeff497e33de8057919", "question": "How many points did LeBron James score in his very first NBA game?", "answer": "25", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be9d", "question": "What bathroom cleaner was originally advertised by the Scrubbing Bubbles?", "answer": "Dow bathroom cleaner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be48", "question": "What word would best describe Port Salut?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8c", "question": "What is the colorful stage name of singer Alecia Moore?", "answer": "Pink", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a90", "question": "Dr. Brown's puppy in \"Back to the Future Part II\" was named after what astronomer?", "answer": "Copernicus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0c", "question": "What is the primary ingredient in Soy Sauce, besides water?", "answer": "Wheat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff1423ab0ee8c595b6d39ab", "question": "What is the name of the thousand-year-old secret society depicted in \"The Da Vinci Code\"?", "answer": "Priory Of Sion", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fb08642cf631c2414a13b54", "question": "In the TV show \"Friends\", what was Joey\u2019s nickname while working at Alessandro\u2019s?", "answer": "Dragon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c98f877e98cb977789f6", "question": "In which city was the oldest university in Scandinavia founded in 1477?", "answer": "Uppsala", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a61", "question": "What disco queen's first gold record was 1975's \"Love to Love You Baby\"?", "answer": "Donna Summer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febb2ed7e83c707845b2115", "question": "\"Sonar\" stands for what?", "answer": "Sound Navigation And Ranging", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fc2f46bcee580c7f8fd1e58", "question": "What is the state animal for Florida?", "answer": "Panther", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a8", "question": "What nation was led by Rameses the Great?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b92e", "question": "How many properties are there on a standard Monopoly board?", "answer": "28", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a25b", "question": "Which English county was Alfred Hitchcock born in?", "answer": "Essex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007804ebd51d85e222ab643", "question": "What offshoot of Cubism was influenced by the work of dye chemist Eug\u00e8ne Chevreul?", "answer": "Orphism\u00a0or\u00a0Orphic Cubism focused on pure abstraction and bright colors. The movement was influenced by Fauvism.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa1", "question": "What legendary jazz trumpeter was nicknamed \"Satchmo\"?", "answer": "Louie Armstrong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358c515db0d66a186cb55d", "question": "What month is the Calgary Stampede held in?", "answer": "July", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b102", "question": "What was explorer Ponce de Leon's first name?", "answer": "Juan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b308", "question": "Who received a speeding ticket while driving his Porsche Spyder on September 30, 1955?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ae8641c7f28483af1e7fdcd", "question": "In which year did India gain its independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1947", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a318", "question": "Which pop duo consisted of Fab Morvan and Rob Pilatus?", "answer": "Milli Vanilli", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a432", "question": "In what country would you most likely encounter a Tasmanian devil?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c591", "question": "What important sensory organ do earthworms lack?", "answer": "Eyes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a7", "question": "Who played Mad Max Rockatansky?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc0", "question": "Whose profile is displayed on the Purple Heart medal?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b696", "question": "What appears with the king of diamonds on a standard English deck of cards?", "answer": "An axe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c65a", "question": "Roadrunners are members of which family of bird?", "answer": "Cuckoos", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b0", "question": "Who beat Martina Navratilova in the Wimbledon Women's Singles final in 1994?", "answer": "Conchita Martinez", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f3", "question": "What sport was once contested with a spadroon?", "answer": "Fencing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b675", "question": "What was William Fox Talbot a pioneer of?", "answer": "Photography", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba6", "question": "What Wyoming National Monument is featured in the movie \"Close Encounters of the Third Kind\"?", "answer": "Devil's Tower", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2cc", "question": "Which 1947 film, starring Cary Grant and Loretta Young was directed by Henry Koster?", "answer": "The Bishop's Wife", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96c6b23c87fd04dd15e24", "question": "What instrument did Paul McCartney primarily play as a member of the Beatles?", "answer": "Bass", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cd0", "question": "The goddess Athena was responsible for causing whose hair to turn into snakes?", "answer": "Medusa", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59c1cdc27bd84c0ea43ad42e", "question": "Skopje is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Macedonia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd8", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"hula\"?", "answer": "Hawaiian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395fd", "question": "\"Pizza the Hut\" was the villain in what sci-fi spoof?", "answer": "Spaceballs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c529877e98cb977789ac", "question": "The Griffith Observatory is located where?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b57187367df192a942e335f", "question": "Tierra del Fuego is divided between which two South American countries?", "answer": "Chile and Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c80b", "question": "Which of the four bases of DNA isn't found in RNA?", "answer": "Thymine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1da", "question": "Before his ears were cut off in 1990 by a political rival, what nation was ruled by dictator Samuel Doe?", "answer": "Liberia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d72", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Modern Prometheus\"?", "answer": "Frankenstein", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d2", "question": "What guitar player was the last act to perform at the original Woodstock in 1969?", "answer": "Jimi Hendrix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a34b", "question": "Which African country was the setting for the TV serial \"The Flame Trees of Thika\"?", "answer": "Kenya", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b278", "question": "During one of his famous freedom-of-speech cases, who wore an American flag to court as a diaper?", "answer": "Larry Flynt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eff", "question": "What artist painted himself sketching on the far right edge of his painting \"The Gross Clinic\"?", "answer": "Thomas Eakins", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa5", "question": "What was the nickname of the Spice Girls singer Geri Halliwell?", "answer": "Ginger Spice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7161a9e54d890926f6de", "question": "What is the capital city of Paraguay?", "answer": "Asuncion", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390f5", "question": "What is the middle name of author H. G. Wells?", "answer": "George", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d074f1a1c922dd1ac64b7", "question": "Who was both the 22nd and the 24th president of the United States?", "answer": "Grover Cleveland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f3b", "question": "What two long-running 1980s TV shows featured characters called Uncle Jesse?", "answer": "The Dukes of Hazzard and Full House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb2", "question": "According to the bible, how many Horsemen of the Apocalypse were there?", "answer": "4", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d2", "question": "What performer led a band known as the Comets?", "answer": "Bill Haley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c059", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Latvia?", "answer": "White wagtail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6b7a3fb6c85e9e634ff4c", "question": "Which comet is visible every 74 to 79 years?", "answer": "Halley's comet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe4", "question": "What two countries share land borders with Tunisia?", "answer": "Algeria and Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6000ef089a72b906b34e3cf8", "question": "What is the product of a body\u2019s mass and its linear velocity?", "answer": "Momentum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ce", "question": "What are the names of the Pep Boys?", "answer": "Manny, Moe, and Jack", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c708", "question": "Dry ice is the frozen form of what gas?", "answer": "Carbon dioxide", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba09", "question": "Who won 7 gold medals in swimming at the 1972 Summer Olympics in Munich?", "answer": "Mark Spitz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aad9", "question": "Edmonton is the capital of which Canadian province?", "answer": "Alberta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2aa", "question": "What type of cancer did actor Humphrey Bogart die from?", "answer": "Esophageal cancer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea34ceff048f679a45aafc", "question": "Which is the oldest planet in our solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339784", "question": "What saxophonist released the 1964 album \"A Love Supreme\"?", "answer": "John Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab26", "question": "What separates Madagascar from Mozambique?", "answer": "Mozambique Channel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b77601dd7bf43be5e7e5", "question": "What menu item do the British call a \"chip butty\"?", "answer": "French fry sandwich", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60121b2963c99d48cd169b0c", "question": "A soniferous object produces what?", "answer": "Sound -- Soniferous animals don\u2019t just make sound, it\u2019s an especially loud and far-reaching sound.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ea", "question": "What TV show began with the words \"There is nothing wrong with your television set.\"?", "answer": "The Outer Limits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ef8601dd7bf43be5e7f3", "question": "What pasta gets its name because of its resemblance to a feather quill?", "answer": "Penne", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdbc", "question": "What is traditionally the main fruit ingredient in tepenade?", "answer": "Olives", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c173", "question": "What is a clarsach?", "answer": "A Gaelic Harp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062c2fc9d816e292245c2a", "question": "How many paintings did Vincent Van Gogh sell during his lifetime?", "answer": "He created more than 900 paintings, yet sold only\u00a0one\u00a0during his lifetime, \"Red Vineyard at Arles\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c581", "question": "Which planet has a year that lasts 88 days?", "answer": "Mercury", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bfc", "question": "Which character did Mickey Rooney play in the movie \"Breakfast at Tiffany's\"?", "answer": "Mr. Yunioshi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339349", "question": "What spin-off from the TV show \"All In The Family\" starred Sally Struthers?", "answer": "Gloria", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc4176ce05a3942286f2c", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Ain't That A Kick In The Head\"?", "answer": "Dean Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397cb", "question": "Who won an Oscar for \"Best Actress\" for her role in \"Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf\"?", "answer": "Elizabeth Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f0", "question": "What was known as \"Bolshaya Gora\" when it was part of Russia?", "answer": "Mount Foraker", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59c1cdfe7bd84c0ea43ad432", "question": "Which city is directly northwest of Windsor, Ontario?", "answer": "Detroit", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b780", "question": "What city's Summer Olympics had the beaver Amik as their mascot?", "answer": "Montreal's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a781", "question": "What is the capital of Portugal?", "answer": "Lisbon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd0", "question": "In what ominous numbered room is Winston Smith strapped to a chair at the end of \"Nineteen Eighty-Four\"?", "answer": "Room 101", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60078261bd51d85e222ab657", "question": "What artist believed he was a reincarnation of his dead brother?", "answer": "When he was five, Dali's parents told him he was a reincarnation of his older brother, who died nine months before he was born.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a912", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Sumter?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29b", "question": "Which English director founded the Theatre Workshop?", "answer": "Joan Littlewood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392c5", "question": "Eric Carmen's hit song \"Hungry Eyes\" has been used in a popular TV ad campaign for what snack food?", "answer": "M&Ms", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339533", "question": "Who was Larry Sanders' sidekick on \"The Larry Sanders Show\"?", "answer": "Hank Kingsley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad1b", "question": "\"Remember the Maine!\" was the rallying cry for what war?", "answer": "The Spanish-American War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a847", "question": "What is the name of the seismic fault line located at the conjunction of Missouri, Arkansas, and Tennessee?", "answer": "New Madrid", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c79", "question": "What animal is Indiana Jones afraid of?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339404", "question": "What is the name of Nicole Kidman's character in the 2001 movie \"Moulin Rouge!\"?", "answer": "Satine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd79", "question": "What open-faced Italian omelette is, despite its name, more often baked than fried?", "answer": "Frittata", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1c9", "question": "Who was the last European head of state to be executed after being removed from power?", "answer": "Nicolae Ceausescu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4bd", "question": "What part of the eye changes shape in LASIK surgery?", "answer": "The cornea", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60062c98c9d816e292245c2d", "question": "What kind of cans did Andy Warhol famously paint?", "answer": "Campbell's Soup Cans\u00a0is a work of art consisting of 32 canvases, each painted with a Campbell's Soup can.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c1", "question": "Coq au vin is a dish made with which type of meat?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4b1", "question": "Which planet in our solar system has a moon named Phoebe?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a19a", "question": "Which two TV series from the 1980s featured a character named Uncle Jesse?", "answer": "Full House and The Dukes of Hazzard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f6fb1a9e54d890926f6d2", "question": "Which country is home to the colorful Rainbow Mountain?", "answer": "Peru -- AKA Vinicunca, it achieves its vibrant hues thanks to natural weathering, which has exposed mineral strips in the earth.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b987", "question": "In which year was the wearing of seat belts made compulsory in the UK?", "answer": "1983", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338af3", "question": "What was Dr. Seuss' real name?", "answer": "Theodor Seuss Geisel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab28", "question": "Antananarivo is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb5", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Lasky?", "answer": "Grape", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b539", "question": "What non-alcoholic syrup is made from pomegranate juice?", "answer": "Grenadine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8a", "question": "What type of stuffed animal does an arctophile collect?", "answer": "Teddy bears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ebe", "question": "Whose series of thirteen children's books of thirteen chapters each ended in 2006 with \"The End\"?", "answer": "Lemony Snicket's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a058", "question": "Adrenalize, Retro Active, and Pyromania are albums from which British hard rock band?", "answer": "Def Leppard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c250", "question": "What do you call an animal that eats both plants and animals?", "answer": "An Omnivore", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb582f5dad637d903c880f", "question": "What animal is considered to be symbolic of Venice?", "answer": "Lion -- The Lion of St. Mark is a symbol that appears throughout the city.  It honors St. Mark, who is the patron saint of Venice.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffa4019c73aa70ea0b70b07", "question": "Which district in central Tokyo is particularly famous for its electronics?", "answer": "Akihabara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b178", "question": "When did the Sydney Opera House officially open its doors to the public?", "answer": "20 October 1973", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339532", "question": "What show featured the five orphaned Salinger siblings?", "answer": "Party of Five", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6bbd0fb6c85e9e634ff59", "question": "What is the word \"laser\" short for?", "answer": "Light amplification by stimulated emission of radiation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921b", "question": "What instrument did Sting play with the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Bass guitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66f4952a821ff76ae8b1e", "question": "In Skamania County, Washington, it\u2019s illegal to kill what creature?", "answer": "Bigfoot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c58c", "question": "What celestial body orbits the Earth?", "answer": "The moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6018bc8dd96d05b23b281657", "question": "Which country was the first to legalize same-sex marriage?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdc0c99469bb8041d07a053", "question": "What type of horse is named from the Spanish word meaning \"painted\"?", "answer": "Pinto", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c978", "question": "What mineral is also referred to as \"Fool's gold\"?", "answer": "Pyrite", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc40", "question": "What nationality is tennis player Roger Federer?", "answer": "Swiss", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3d6cff048f679a45ab4d", "question": "From which language does the name \"coyote\" originate?", "answer": "Aztec", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c08", "question": "What year was model Anna Nicole Smith born?", "answer": "1967", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b316", "question": "On April 11, 1990, California Angel Mike Witt combined with which starter to pitch a no-hit victory?", "answer": "Mark Langston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f9b", "question": "What's the appropriate stage name of musician Richard Melville Hall?", "answer": "Moby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ec", "question": "Which continental South American country borders Panama?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ad7eba2b24f84e0b9f9ffdf", "question": "What town's name means \"House of Bread\" in Hebrew?", "answer": "Bethlehem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59a551be3e1c6f9840ba318f", "question": "Corfu is part of which country?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133887f", "question": "What novel did Ian Fleming introduce James Bond in?", "answer": "Casino Royale", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a405", "question": "What city is the capital of Northwest Territories in Canada?", "answer": "Yellowknife", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa5", "question": "Minsk is the capital of which European country?", "answer": "Belarus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b838", "question": "What 1960s invention was originally called the \"Pleasure Pit\"?", "answer": "Waterbed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339542", "question": "What kind of dog is Ren on \"The Ren and Stimpy Show\"?", "answer": "Chihuahua", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aed", "question": "What is Charlie's last name in Roald Dahl's \"Charlie and the Chocolate Factory\"?", "answer": "Bucket", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ce", "question": "Turnov, Rusty and Bobo appear in what stage musical?", "answer": "Starlight Express", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c539", "question": "What artificial sweetener based on sucralose was introduced in 1999?", "answer": "Splenda", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be28", "question": "What world's currency is the Linden dollar?", "answer": "Second Life", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab90", "question": "What was Cambodia once known as?", "answer": "Khmer Empire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81c", "question": "In what part of the body would you find aqueous humour?", "answer": "The eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd9734b23c87fd04dd15e58", "question": "Who was the first person to single-handedly sail around the world?", "answer": "Joshua Slocum", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b067", "question": "Which Space Shuttle broke apart during re-entry in February, 2003?", "answer": "Columbia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "595642f2803c1f1ebcc4a02e", "question": "Who took home the Academy of Country Music\u2019s Male Vocalist trophy every year between 2006 and 2010?", "answer": "Brad Paisley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6a", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Ray\"?", "answer": "Jamie Foxx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a690", "question": "What three states share a border with New Hampshire?", "answer": "Maine, Massachusetts and Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe2", "question": "Tunisia is part of which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a081", "question": "What is the name of the lead singer for the Canadian rock band Rush?", "answer": "Geddy Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c7", "question": "In the game \"Plants vs Zombies\", what do players collect as currency to buy plants?", "answer": "Sunlight", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339038", "question": "Which music genre lilterally means \"new trend\" in Portuguese?", "answer": "Bossa Nova", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a743", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Old Line State\"?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cdd69e347d002c297e4f0", "question": "What are affected by Phylloxera?", "answer": "Grapevines", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b544", "question": "What does Pinocchio in Italian mean?", "answer": "Pine eyes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d7d", "question": "What disease affects the protagonist in the film \"My Left Foot\"?", "answer": "Cerebral palsy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bb3", "question": "How many symphonies did Beethoven compose?", "answer": "9", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a36", "question": "On what show did Heather Locklear make her TV debut in a recurring role?", "answer": "Dynasty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5f8", "question": "What US city is nicknamed the \"Crossroads of the West\"?", "answer": "Salt Lake City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc33eec223966ae8f887c", "question": "What actor won the inaugural Razzie Redeemer Award by going from a flop (Gigli) to hits (Argo and Gone Girl)?", "answer": "Ben Affleck", "category": "entertainment"}]